mahara.org 2013-05-23

# Privacy statement - Mahara ePortfolio System

## Privacy Statement

### Introduction

We are committed to protecting your privacy and providing users with a safe and functional personal learning and development environment. This Statement of Privacy applies to the mahara.org site and governs data collection and usage.

### Collection of personal information

By registering on mahara.org you will be required to provide us with a certain amount of personal information. We will not disclose any of your personal information to any other person or organisation without your written consent unless authorised or required by law.

### Cookies

In order to use mahara.org you must have cookies enabled within your browser. Please note that no personal information is stored within the cookies used in mahara.org.

A cookie is a data file that is placed on your computer by a webpage server. Cookies are not programs, spyware or viruses and are unable to perform any operation by themselves.

### How we use your personal information

We will only use your personal information for the purpose for which you provided it to us.

As mahara.org users you are able to determine what personal information you make available to others. By default, unless assigned Administrator, Staff or Tutor access rights, a user may only view your Preferred Name. This includes listings within a Notification report or Visitor Log.

We may also collect system usage for statistical purposes however this data will not identify any individual.

### Storage and security of your personal information

We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that any personal information we hold is not subject to loss or misuse or unauthorised access, disclosure or alteration.

In order to help protect your personal information, please do not disclose your Username or Password to person other than the Site Administrator.

### Changes to this privacy statement

We may occasionally make adjustments to our privacy statement to reflect changes to the system and in response to customer feedback. As such we suggest you check the Privacy Statement each time you visit this site.

### Contact

If you have any questions regarding this Statement or believe we have not adhered to the above criteria, please Contact Us and we will use all reasonable efforts to remedy the issue.
